const quizQuestions4en = [{
    question:"To what temperature should the oxyfuel flame heat the surface to be cut, before opening the oxygen jet?",
    answers: ["Up to the ignition temperature of the material.",
    "Up to the material's melting temperature.",
    "Up to the material vaporization temperature.",
    "Up to material stress relief temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The noise level of the gouging process is very high due to:",
    answers: ["the pulsed current used in gouging;",
    "a high flow rate of compressed air used to expel the molten metal;",
    "the high frequency current used in this process;",
    "a high arc voltage, typical for this process."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the correct technique to weld with coated electrode in the flat position?",
    answers: ["Pushing (forehand technique).",
    "With the electrode at a perpendicular as possible position.",
    "Pulling (backhand or drag technique).",
    "With weaving motion."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the correct technique to weld with coated electrode in the vertical upwards position?",
    answers: ["Pushing (forehand technique).",
    "With the electrode at a perpendicular as possible position.",
    "Pulling (backhand or drag technique).",
    "Backhand (pulling) with weaving motion."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Gouging is an operation aiming:",
    answers: ["weld finishing;",
    "groove preparation;",
    "removal of defective part of the weld;",
    "joining light metals (aluminium and its alloys)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is not a function of the coating on covered electrodes:",
    answers: ["to protect the weld pool;",
    "to provide alloying elements;",
    "to increase the deposition rate;",
    "to minimize the emission of harmful fumes to the welder."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What material can be cut by plasma cutting process but not be cut by oxy cutting?",
    answers: ["Aluminium.",
    "Thin plates (less than 5 mm) of carbon steel.",
    "Thick plates (over 100 mm) of carbon steel.",
    "Galvanized sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An increase of the arc welding speed:",
    answers: ["does not change penetration;",
    "can cause increased penetration and wider welds;",
    "may cause less penetration and narrower welds;",
    "may cause less penetration and wider welds."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MIG/MAG welding, one of the main functions of the shielding gas is:",
    answers: ["protect the weld pool from atmospheric oxygen and nitrogen;",
    "protect the welder's eyes from electric arc sparks;",
    "increase the electrode fusion rate;",
    "increase welding speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is another function of solid wire in MIG/MAG welding, besides of depositing filler metal?",
    answers: ["To create slag to protect the weld pool.",
    "To reduce alloying elements in the weld pool.",
    "To introduce alloying elements into the weld metal.",
    "To generate a shielding gas."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which alternative is correct in relation to the MIG/MAG (GMAW) process?",
    answers: ["It is an electric arc welding process with gas shielding and the bare solid wire electrode that is continuously fed.",
    "The MIG/MAG process has independent control of the heat source and filler metal addition.",
    "MIG/MAG welding is not applied to aluminium alloys due to the impossibility of using alternating current for cathodic cleaning of oxides.",
    "This welding process can be used manually, semi-automatically, automatically and robotically."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The constant current type power source is best suited for:",
    answers: ["welding with tubular electrode (FCAW);",
    "submerged arc welding (SAW) with fine wires;",
    " welding with covered electrode (MMA/SMAW);",
    "MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The constant current type power source is best suited for:",
    answers: ["welding with tubular electrode (FCAW);",
    " TIG (GTAW) welding;",
    "submerged arc welding (SAW) with fine wires;",
    "MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It exerts decisive influence on metal transfer during MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["The current density in the wire and the type of filler metal.",
    "the value of the welding current and the welding speed;",
    "the type of shielding gas and its flow;",
    "the inductance of the constant current type power source."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It exerts decisive influence on metal transfer during MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["the value of the welding current and the welding speed;",
    "the type of shielding gas and its flow;",
    "the type of shielding gas and the arc length;",
    "the inductance of the constant current type power source."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is not a function of the coating on covered electrodes:",
    answers: ["to facilitate ionization and promote arc stabilization;",
    "to protect the weld pool against contamination by atmospheric gases;",
    "to reduce welding thermal stresses;",
    "to produce slag on the weld surface."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The most commonly used types of covered electrode coating are:",
    answers: ["basic, rutile and of high hardness one;",
    "basic, combined and cellulosic;",
    "rutile, cellulosic and of high deposit one;",
    "basic, rutile and cellulosic."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding submerged arc welding (SAW), mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The equipment is simple, portable and its cost is relatively low.",
    "Welding can be carried out in all positions, in different materials, including dissimilar materials.",
    "Used mainly in thicker materials, due to the large volume of the weld pool, which makes it difficult to weld thinner plates.",
    "The submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding submerged arc welding (SAW), mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The equipment is simple, portable and its cost is relatively low.",
    "It is insensitive to air currents.",
    "Welding can be carried out in all positions, in different materials, including dissimilar materials.",
    "The submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the parameterization of the TIG (GTAW) process, in which option are the process parameters directly related to each other?",
    answers: ["The welding speed and the penetration (for the same current).",
    "The welding current and the arc length.",
    "The welding speed and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The pointing (sharpening) angle of the electrode and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the parameterization of the TIG (GTAW) process, in which option are the process parameters directly related to each other?",
    answers: ["The welding current and the arc length.",
    "The arc voltage and the bead width.",
    "The welding speed and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The pointing (sharpening) angle of the electrode and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the parameterization of the TIG (GTAW) process, in which option are the process parameters directly related to each other?",
    answers: ["The welding current and the arc length.",
    "The welding speed and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The welding current and the shielding gas flow rate.",
    "The pointing (sharpening) angle of the electrode and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the parameterization of the TIG (GTAW) process, in which option are the process parameters directly related to each other?",
    answers: ["The welding current and the arc length.",
    "The welding speed and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The pointing (sharpening) angle of the electrode and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The sheet thickness and the welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the parameterization of the TIG (GTAW) process, in which option are the process parameters directly related to each other?",
    answers: ["The welding current and the penetration.",
    "The welding current and the arc length.",
    "Welding speed and shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The pointing (sharpening) angle of the electrode and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the parameterization of the TIG (GTAW) process, in which option are the process parameters directly related to each other?",
    answers: ["The welding current and the arc length.",
    "The welding current and the nozzle size.",
    "The welding speed and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The pointing (sharpening) angle of the electrode and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the parameterization of the TIG (GTAW) process, in which option are the process parameters directly related to each other?",
    answers: ["The welding current and the arc length.",
    "The welding speed and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current).",
    "The arc length and the arc voltage.",
    "The pointing (sharpening) angle of the electrode and the shielding gas flow rate (for the same current)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The main application of TIG (GTAW) welding is for:",
    answers: ["Thin low carbon steel tubes and for root passes in thick carbon steel tubes. ",
    "Thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Filling passes of the multipass joint in thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Welding in overhead position of joints in thick and thin carbon steel plates and tubes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The main application of TIG (GTAW) welding is for:",
    answers: ["Thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Thick and thin stainless steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Filling passes of the multipass joint in thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Welding in overhead position of joints in thick and thin carbon steel plates and tubes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The main application of TIG (GTAW) welding is for:",
    answers: ["Thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Filling passes of the multipass joint in thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Thick and thin sheets and tubes of aluminium and its alloys.",
    "Welding in overhead position of joints in thick and thin carbon steel plates and tubes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The main application of TIG (GTAW) welding is for:",
    answers: ["Thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Filling passes of the multipass joint in thick and thin carbon steel sheets and tubes.",
    "Welding in overhead position of joints in thick and thin carbon steel plates and tubes.",
    "Low carbon steel sheets with thicknesses less than 1.5 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What does the low-pressure gauge, installed on the gas cylinder regulator used in oxygas cutting or welding, show?",
    answers: ["Pressure inside the cylinder.",
    "Pressure needed for work.",
    "Atmosphere pressure.",
    "Average pressure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What does the high-pressure gauge, installed on the gas cylinder regulator used in oxygas cutting or welding, show?",
    answers: ["Pressure inside the cylinder.",
    "Pressure needed for work.",
    "Atmosphere pressure.",
    "Average pressure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Oxygas welding is applicable for:",
    answers: ["Sheet steel not thicker than 5 mm, usually up to 2 to 3 mm thick.",
    "Steel tubes up to 150 mm in diameter in all positions except the overhead position.",
    "Steel sheets without thickness limit, applying the multipass technique.",
    "Steel pipes up to 500 mm in diameter and more than 12 mm thick."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Oxygas welding is applicable for:",
    answers: ["Sheet steel not thicker than 10 mm in all positions except overhead position.",
    "Steel tubes up to 150 mm in diameter and up to 2 to 3 mm thick.",
    "Steel sheets without thickness limit, applying the multipass technique.",
    "Steel pipes up to 500 mm in diameter and more than 12 mm thick."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct regarding a welding power source with a duty cycle of 300 A/60%?",
    answers: ["This power source is rated to deliver 300 A for 6 minutes in a 10 minute period.",
    "This power source is rated to deliver 300 A for 3 minutes in a 5 minute period.",
    "This power source is rated to deliver 180 A (60% of 300 A) for a period of 10 minutes.",
    "This power source is rated to deliver a maximum of 50 A for 6 minutes (50 x 6 = 300) in a 10 minute period."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why is solid steel wire for MIG/MAG welding normally copper plated?",
    answers: ["To prevent weld oxidation and to avoid spatter generation.",
    "To improve wire feedability and ensure good electrical contact at the contact tip.",
    "To prevent weld oxidation and ensure good current distribution at the contact tip.",
    "To decrease spatter and increase penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Covered electrode developed for alternating current (AC) welding can be used with:",
    answers: ["any type of current (AC, DCEN and DCEP) without restrictions.",
    "AC and with DCEN or DCEP as per the manufacturer's specification.",
    "AC and with DCEN (DCEP is not recommended).",
    "AC and with DCEP (DCEN is not recommended)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Total losses of covered electrodes can reach 30% – 35% due to:",
    answers: ["the electrode stub loss (the grip end of the covered electrode).",
    "a very low current specified by the manufacturer.",
    "a high no-load voltage of the power sources used in this welding process.",
    "the fact that the core is melted faster than the coating."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Total losses of covered electrodes can reach 30% – 35% due to:",
    answers: ["a very low current specified by the manufacturer.",
    "longer stub losses (10 - 15 cm stubs discarded by the welder).",
    "a high no-load voltage of the power sources used in this welding process.",
    "the fact that the core is melted faster than the coating."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Total losses of covered electrodes can reach 30% – 35% due to:",
    answers: ["a very low current specified by the manufacturer.",
    "a high no-load voltage of the power sources used in this welding process.",
    "mishandling (electrodes discarded due to damaged coating).",
    "the fact that the core is melted faster than the coating."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Total losses of covered electrodes can reach 30% – 35% due to:",
    answers: ["a very low current specified by the manufacturer.",
    "a high no-load voltage of the power sources used in this welding process.",
    "the fact that the core is melted faster than the coating.",
    "\"a low skill of the welder letting the electrode to \"\"stick\"\" to the workpiece with the subsequent destruction of the coating (at the moment of its separation from the workpiece).\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say regarding welding with covered electrode:",
    answers: ["the main metallurgical functions of the coating are the protection of the molten metal against the atmospheric contamination and control of the weld metal chemical composition.",
    "the welding speed is influenced, among others, by the arc voltage.",
    "the process is very sensitive to wind and drafts, which makes it difficult to use outdoors.",
    "the arc length is kept more constant due to the self-adjustment offered by the Constant Voltage power source."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say regarding welding with covered electrode:",
    answers: ["the welding speed is influenced, among others, by the arc voltage.",
    "there is a material transfer jet due to a projective sheath (crater) formed at the electrode tip, due to the delay of the coating burn in relation to the core.",
    "the process is very sensitive to wind and drafts, which makes it difficult to use outdoors.",
    " arc length is kept more constant due to the self-adjustment offered by the Constant Voltage power source."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say regarding welding with covered electrode:",
    answers: ["the welding speed is influenced, among others, by the arc voltage.",
    "the process is very sensitive to wind and drafts, which makes it difficult to use outdoors.",
    "the welding speed is influenced, among others, by the applied welding current.",
    " arc length is kept more constant due to the self-adjustment offered by the Constant Voltage power source."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say regarding welding with covered electrode:",
    answers: ["the welding speed is influenced, among others, by the arc voltage.",
    "the process is very sensitive to wind and drafts, which makes it difficult to use outdoors.",
    " arc length is kept more constant due to the self-adjustment offered by the Constant Voltage power source.",
    "Larger electrode diameters are preferable for welding thick plates or in the flat position, while smaller diameters are more suitable for welding thin sheets or in out of position."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The use of basic covered electrodes is preferable when:",
    answers: ["a bead surface with low irregularity is required;",
    "better mechanical properties are required, mainly the impact toughness;",
    "welding in vertical downward position is required;",
    "a high penetration is required."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to oxygas welding:",
    answers: ["Propane is the most used for the oxygas welding process, due to its high combustion power and low cost.",
    "The more oxygen in the gas mixture, the more easily reactive materials are welded together, as the reaction of metal with oxygen is exothermic.",
    "May or may not use filler metal.",
    "The combustion of fuel gas (e.g., acetylene) takes place only with oxygen from the atmosphere, which makes the process very economical."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which shielding gas do you consider appropriate to be used in TIG welding?",
    answers: ["Pure argon, for most materials.",
    "High purity argon for copper.",
    "Pure helium for aluminium (requirement imposed by a very high thermal conductivity of aluminium, even in thin sheets).",
    "Argon mixed with CO2 for carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"If the welding current is fixed, which gas (or gas mixture) will promote the deepest penetration in the GTAW/TIG process?",
    answers: ["Pure argon.",
    "Argon + helium mixture.",
    "Pure helium.",
    "Helium + CO2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The DCEP polarity with TIG welding (GTAW):",
    answers: ["will require a large diameter electrode;",
    "will not remove the aluminium oxide;",
    "will increase the penetration;",
    "will increase the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"If the welding current is fixed, which gas will promote the deepest penetration when using the GTAW (TIG welding) process?",
    answers: ["Argon.",
    "Helium.",
    "Pure CO2.",
    "Ar + H2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The most common gas used for welding aluminium with GTAW (TIG welding) is:",
    answers: ["Helium.",
    "Argon.",
    "Argon with 1% - 2% of oxygen.",
    "Argon with 1% - 2% of nitrogen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What type of wire feeder is preferable for constant current power sources?",
    answers: ["Arc voltage sensing units.",
    "Constant speed units.",
    "Inductance controlled units.",
    "Synergy controlled units."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What causes electrical connections to heat up?",
    answers: ["Dirty contact surfaces.",
    "Too large contact area.",
    "Too tight contact surfaces. ",
    "Its high electrical conductivity. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What causes electrical connections to heat up?",
    answers: ["Too large contact area.",
    "Loose contact surfaces. ",
    "Too tight contact surfaces. ",
    "Its high electrical conductivity. "],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What causes electrical connections to heat up?",
    answers: ["Too large contact area.",
    "Too tight contact surfaces. ",
    "Resistance to current flow.",
    "Its high electrical conductivity. "],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What causes electrical connections to heat up?",
    answers: ["Too large contact area.",
    "Too tight contact surfaces. ",
    "Its high electrical conductivity. ",
    "Too small contact area."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which of the options below are the welding processes arranged in increasing order of imposed energy density?",
    answers: ["Resistance spot < laser < electron beam < oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Oxy-fuel gas < resistance spot < arc < electron beam welding.",
    "Oxy-fuel gas < arc < resistance spot < electron beam welding.",
    "Arc < resistance spot < electron beam < oxy-fuel gas welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which of the options below are the welding processes arranged in increasing order of imposed energy density?",
    answers: ["Resistance spot < laser < electron beam < oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Oxy-fuel gas < arc < resistance spot < laser welding.",
    "Oxy-fuel gas < resistance spot < arc < electron beam welding.",
    "Arc < resistance spot < electron beam < oxy-fuel gas welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which of the options below are the welding processes arranged in decreasing order of imposed energy density?",
    answers: ["Resistance spot > laser > electron beam > oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Laser > arc > resistance spot > oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Electron beam > resistance spot > arc > oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Arc > resistance spot > electron beam > oxy-fuel gas welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which of the options below are the welding processes arranged in decreasing order of imposed energy density?",
    answers: ["Resistance spot > laser > electron beam > oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Laser > resistance spot > arc > oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Electron beam > arc > resistance spot > oxy-fuel gas welding.",
    "Arc > resistance spot > electron beam > oxy-fuel gas welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The gases used in gas protection have the following function:",
    answers: ["To cool down the workpiece and the electrode.",
    "To transfer the filler metal to the weld.",
    "To transfer alloy elements to the weld pool.",
    "To protect the active area of the weld (the arc, the weld pool and around them) against contamination by atmospheric gases."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding welding by the self-protected Tubular Electrode Process, indicate the correct statement:",
    answers: ["the protection of the weld pool is ensured by the torch nozzle;",
    "the protection of the weld pool is obtained with gases and slag originated from the wire core;",
    "unlike the MIG/MAG (GMAW) process, the wire feed speed varies during welding;",
    "the power source static characteristic of Constant Current type is recommended for this welding process."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"\"Why is the electric welding arc called \"\"arc\"\", despite having a truncated conical shape?\"",
    answers: ["It is a term borrowed from another language, where it means “conical trunk”.",
    "It is a typical term for electrical discharges (e.g., “rainbow”).",
    "Because when was observed for the first time between two horizontal electrodes of graphite, it assumed this format.",
    "It only seems to have a truncated conical shape, but it is made up of many parallel arcs that together form this visible equivocal shape."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical feature of welding operations:",
    answers: ["High production cost.",
    "It can be applied to a wide variety of metals and alloys.",
    "In semi-automatic processes, the professionalism of the workmanship has little influence on the quality of the product.",
    "The union quality is good, although the process itself is slow."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical feature of welding operations:",
    answers: ["High production cost.",
    "It can be mechanized, standardizing the production, and used for both very small and very large parts.",
    "In semi-automatic processes, the professionalism of the workmanship has little influence on the quality of the product.",
    "The union quality is good, although the process itself is slow."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The energy from a power source is used to:",
    answers: ["heat the electrode;",
    "obtain a smooth finish on the weld surface;",
    "ensure the required chemical composition of the weld metal;",
    "increase the thermal efficiency of the arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The energy from a power source is used to:",
    answers: ["obtain a smooth finish on the weld surface;",
    "heat the workpiece;",
    "ensure the required chemical composition of the weld metal;",
    "increase the thermal efficiency of the arc."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The energy from a power source is used to:",
    answers: ["obtain a smooth finish on the weld surface;",
    "ensure the required chemical composition of the weld metal;",
    "increase the thermal efficiency of the arc;",
    "compensate for all heat losses in the welding circuit."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a function of the tubular electrode wire?",
    answers: ["Create slag to protect the weld pool.",
    "Reduce spatter generation.",
    "Enable the welding of thinner sheets.",
    "Improve base metal wettability in aluminium alloy welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a function of the tubular electrode wire?",
    answers: ["Enable the welding of thinner sheets.",
    "Reduce spatter generation.",
    "Deposit alloying elements in the weld metal.",
    "Improve base metal wettability in aluminium alloy welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is a function of the tubular electrode wire?",
    answers: ["Enable the welding of thinner sheets.",
    "Reduce spatter generation.",
    "Improve base metal wettability in aluminium alloy welding.",
    "Generate a shielding gas."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MMA (SMAW) welding, what factor favours easier arc striking?",
    answers: ["Larger electrode diameter.",
    "Thinner welding cables (leads).",
    "Basic type electrode.",
    "Special power source features (e.g., Hot Start function)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MMA (SMAW) welding, what factor favours easier arc striking?",
    answers: ["Higher current.",
    "Larger electrode diameter.",
    "Thinner welding cables (leads).",
    "Basic type electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MMA (SMAW) welding, what factor favours easier arc striking?",
    answers: ["Larger electrode diameter.",
    "Rutile type electrode.",
    "Thinner welding cables (leads).",
    "Basic type electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MMA (SMAW) welding, what factor favours easier arc striking?",
    answers: ["Larger electrode diameter.",
    "Thinner welding cables (leads).",
    "Higher no-load voltage.",
    "Basic type electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is NOT a surface preparation technique before welding?",
    answers: ["Cleaning with kerosene and sponge.",
    "Mechanical cleaning with sandpaper.",
    "Mechanical cleaning by grinding",
    "Mechanical cleaning with wire brush."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The ability of a material to withstand a sharp high velocity blow is called:",
    answers: ["yield strength;",
    "mechanical strength;",
    "compressive strength;",
    "impact strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following metals has the highest coefficient of thermal expansion?",
    answers: ["Carbon steel.",
    "Iron.",
    "Copper.",
    "Aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element is not good in steel?",
    answers: ["Chromium.",
    "Phosphorus.",
    "Molybdenum.",
    "Carbon."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element is not good in steel?",
    answers: ["Chromium.",
    "Sulphur.",
    "Molybdenum.",
    "Carbon."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Low carbon steel is not considered hardenable unless it has a carbon content of more than:",
    answers: ["0.10%,",
    "0.20%;",
    "0.30%;",
    "0.40%."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The approximate melting point of copper is:",
    answers: ["660 ºC;",
    "1100 ºC;",
    "1500 ºC;",
    "2200 ºC."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Tool steels are difficult to weld because of:",
    answers: ["a low carbon content;",
    "a high carbon content;",
    "a high hardness;",
    "a high iron content."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following gases are suitable for MIG welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["Argon, helium and mixtures of argon and helium.",
    "Argon and mixtures 95% argon + 5% CO2.",
    "CO2 e nitrogen.",
    "Hydrogen."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hematite is a combination of:",
    answers: ["iron and nitrogen;",
    "iron and coke;",
    "iron and oxygen;",
    "iron and limestone."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a physical property:",
    answers: ["high ductility;",
    "low thermal conductivity;",
    "low tenacity;",
    "low machinability."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a physical property:",
    answers: ["high electrical conductivity;",
    "low thermal conductivity;",
    "low tenacity;",
    "low machinability."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Carbon causes many problems in steels. Why aren't carbonless steels produced?",
    answers: ["Fe-Mn steels, which do not contain carbon, have inferior mechanical properties compared to Fe-C steels.",
    "Fe-Si steels, which do not contain carbon, have inferior mechanical properties compared to Fe-C steels.",
    "Other chemical compounds of iron do not exist, only with carbon.",
    "Steel is a metallic alloy formed by iron and carbon, with percentages of the latter varying between 0.02 and 2%."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Carbon causes many problems in steels. Why aren't carbonless steels produced?",
    answers: ["Fe-Mn steels, which do not contain carbon, have inferior mechanical properties compared to Fe-C steels.",
    "Fe-Si steels, which do not contain carbon, have inferior mechanical properties compared to Fe-C steels.",
    "Other chemical compounds of iron do not exist, only with carbon.",
    "Commercial iron is not good as a building material, as it is very ductile and has low mechanical strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is sulphur (S) added to steels?",
    answers: ["To increase corrosion resistance.",
    "To improve toughness.",
    "Sulphur is not added. It is an impurity.",
    "To improve hardenability."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is phosphorus (P) added to steels?",
    answers: ["To increase corrosion resistance.",
    "To improve toughness.",
    "Phosphorus is not added. It is an impurity.",
    "To improve hardenability."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which statement regarding aluminium properties is correct?",
    answers: ["The thermal conductivity of aluminium is about three times higher than that of iron.",
    "The thermal conductivity of aluminium is about three times higher than that of copper.",
    "The electrical conductivity of aluminium is higher than that of copper.",
    "The electrical conductivity of aluminium is close to that of iron."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mercury has the volumetric thermal expansion:",
    answers: ["lower than copper;",
    "lower than steel;",
    "lower than cast iron;",
    "higher than aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mercury has the electrical conductivity:",
    answers: ["higher than copper;",
    "higher than steel;",
    "higher than silver;",
    "higher than aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is the most important alloy element in stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Nickel.",
    "Vanadium.",
    "Chromium.",
    "Carbon."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"All kinds of stainless steels contain:",
    answers: ["nickel;",
    "vanadium;",
    "chromium;",
    "molybdenum."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Stainless steels are:",
    answers: ["steels with a chromium content until 2%;",
    "steels with high chromium content and often with nickel;",
    "steels with a low content of carbon;",
    "steels with chromium and nickel of the content no less than 10,5% each."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A stainless steel is called ferritic, because of its:",
    answers: ["chemical composition;",
    "processing method;",
    "mechanical properties;",
    "microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A stainless steel is called austenitic, because of its:",
    answers: ["chemical composition;",
    "processing method;",
    "mechanical properties;",
    "microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A stainless steel is called martensitic, because of its:",
    answers: ["chemical composition;",
    "processing method;",
    "mechanical properties;",
    "microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element is not used as an alloying element in aluminium alloys?",
    answers: ["Carbon.",
    "Magnesium.",
    "Manganese.",
    "Silicon."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which alloying element is the most efficient to increase the hardness of steel?",
    answers: ["Carbon.",
    "Sulphur.",
    "Aluminium.",
    "Phosphorus."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When a metal is uniformly heated with no restriction in its expansion, then after cooling:",
    answers: ["it will not return to its original form;",
    "it will return to its original form;",
    "it will get a little bit bigger;",
    "it will be distorted."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The melting point of aluminium is:",
    answers: [" 600 °C;",
    " 620 °C;",
    " 660 °C;",
    " 680 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What does adding carbon do to mild steel?",
    answers: ["An increase in ductility.",
    "An increase in the melting temperature.",
    "An increase in hardenability.",
    "It decreases tensile strength."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Iron makes up approximately ____% or more of the composition of steel:",
    answers: ["65;",
    "75;",
    "85;",
    "95."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the approximate melting temperature of brass?",
    answers: ["1100 ºC",
    "900 ºC",
    "660 ºC",
    "420 ºC"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the approximate melting temperature of bronze?",
    answers: ["1100 ºC",
    "900 ºC",
    "660 ºC",
    "420 ºC"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the approximate melting temperature of lead?",
    answers: ["230 ºC",
    "330 ºC",
    "460 ºC",
    "500 ºC"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mercury has the density:",
    answers: ["lower than copper;",
    "lower than steel;",
    "lower than cast iron;",
    "higher than aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following metals will NOT expand when heated?",
    answers: ["Iron.",
    "Cast iron.",
    "Stainless steel.",
    "Bismuth."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which grade of stainless steel is the most common?",
    answers: ["Austenitic.",
    "Ferritic.",
    "Martensitic.",
    "Duplex."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the difference, in respect to the influence on the steel properties, between Niobium and Columbium alloying elements?",
    answers: ["Niobium is an austenite stabilizer, whereas columbium is a ferrite stabilizer.",
    "Niobium is an austenite former, whereas columbium is a ferrite former.",
    "Niobium is a carbide former, whereas columbium is a carbide stabilizer.",
    "There is no difference, because niobium and columbium are synonymous names for the same chemical element."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following are the two basic elements in austenitic stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Chromium and carbon.",
    "Chromium and iron.",
    "Chromium and molybdenum.",
    "Chromium and manganese."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which two elements are characteristic of austenitic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Chromium and manganese.",
    "Manganese and molybdenum.",
    "Chromium and nickel.",
    "Chromium and vanadium."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What microstructure will low carbon steel have if cooled slowly from the molten state?",
    answers: [" Ferrite and pearlite.",
    "Pearlite.",
    "Ferrite and austenite.",
    "Austenite."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which grade of stainless steel will always remain a face centered cubic structure?",
    answers: ["Austenitic.",
    "Ferritic.",
    "Martensitic.",
    "Duplex."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative in relation to the Fe-C equilibrium diagram:",
    answers: ["Steels and cast irons do not show significant differences in properties because they are both Fe-C alloys;",
    "the Fe-C equilibrium diagram is obtained with rapid cooling (in order not to lose the equilibrium between the phases);",
    "in the Fe-C phase diagram, the cast irons are above the carbon percentage of 1,60%;",
    "in the Fe-C phase diagram, the cast irons are above the carbon percentage of 2,10%;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weld pool in the covered electrode welding process contains material coming from:",
    answers: ["the base metal (workpiece) only;",
    "the base metal (workpiece), electrode and its coating;",
    "the electrode coating only;",
    "the electrode core wire only."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The state of matter that exhibits the least amount of energy is:",
    answers: ["solid;",
    "liquid;",
    "gaseous;",
    "plasma."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"What is the amount of the resultant force at a point if a force of 13 kN and a force of 19 kN are applied at the point along the same line but in opposite directions?",
    answers: ["0 kN (because in this case the forces annul each other).",
    "6 kN.",
    "16 KN.",
    "32 kN."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The strength of materials is affected by several factors. Which of the following is relevant?",
    answers: ["Environmental pressure.",
    "Loading mode (monotonic or cyclic).",
    "Testing machine size.",
    "Testing machine operator experience."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The strength of materials is affected by several factors. Which of the following is relevant?",
    answers: ["Environmental pressure.",
    "Loading type (tension, compression, torsion).",
    "Testing machine size.",
    "Testing machine operator experience."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The strength of materials is affected by several factors. Which of the following is relevant?",
    answers: ["Environmental pressure.",
    "Deformation rate (high or low).",
    "Testing machine size.",
    "Testing machine operator experience."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The strength of materials is affected by several factors. Which of the following is relevant?",
    answers: ["Environmental pressure.",
    "Plastic deformation mode (hot or cold).",
    "Testing machine size.",
    "Testing machine operator experience."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The strength of materials is affected by several factors. Which of the following is relevant?",
    answers: ["Environmental pressure.",
    "Test temperature. ",
    "Testing machine size.",
    "Testing machine operator experience."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding deformations, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Normal stresses cause specific longitudinal deformations with a change in dimensions (volume). Tangential stresses, on the other hand, cause shape-shifting distortions;",
    "When a force is applied to a rigid body, it changes shape and size;",
    "Plastic deformations are fully reversible and proportional to the applied stresses;",
    "Elastic deformations are not proportional to applied stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding deformations, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Plastic deformations are not proportional to applied stresses;",
    "When a force is applied to a rigid body, it changes shape and size;",
    "Plastic deformations are fully reversible and proportional to the applied stresses;",
    "Elastic deformations are not proportional to applied stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the characteristic properties of metallic materials, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The stress beyond which it causes yielding is called the yield point and the strain occurring from this point is called elastic strain;",
    "Usually, the material with greater hardness has greater ductility;",
    "The proportionality limit (elastic limit) of the stress - strain curve is the highest stress for which Hooke's law is valid;",
    "The yield strength of steel, determined by the tensile test, does not depend on the size of the test specimen."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the characteristic properties of metallic materials, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The stress beyond which it causes yielding is called the yield point and the strain occurring from this point is called elastic strain;",
    "Usually, the material with greater hardness has greater ductility;",
    "Ductile materials generally break after undergoing large plastic deformations and brittle materials break with small plastic deformations;",
    "The yield strength of steel, determined by the tensile test, does not depend on the size of the test specimen."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About forces it can be said that:",
    answers: ["To simplify calculations, forces are always considered acting at a single point (concentrated forces);",
    "Forces can be external (both active and reactive) and internal (which are only active without reaction);",
    "Newton's 3rd Law states that the forces of action and reaction between bodies in contact have the same intensity, the same line of action and the same direction;",
    "Two forces acting on a material point can be replaced by a single force, called the resultant, obtained by the diagonal of the parallelogram whose sides are equal to the given forces;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About forces it can be said that:",
    answers: ["To simplify calculations, forces are always considered acting at a single point (concentrated forces);",
    "Forces can be external (both active and reactive) and internal (which are only active without reaction);",
    "Newton's 3rd Law states that the forces of action and reaction between bodies in contact have the same intensity, the same line of action and the same direction;",
    "Force is a vector quantity characterized by its intensity and direction;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About forces it can be said that:",
    answers: ["To simplify calculations, forces are always considered acting at a single point (concentrated forces);",
    "Forces can be external (both active and reactive) and internal (which are only active without reaction);",
    "Newton's 3rd Law states that the forces of action and reaction between bodies in contact have the same intensity, the same line of action and the same direction;",
    "Newton's 2nd law states that if the resultant force acting on a material point is not zero, it will have an acceleration proportional to the intensity of the resultant and in its direction;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"\"A 3 m horizontal cantilever beam is subjected to a vertical load (P) of 100 N at its free end \"\"B\"\". The resulting restraint reactions Pa and Ma at the fixed end \"\"A\"\" are: \"",
    answers: ["Pa = 300 N e Ma = 300 Nm;",
    "Pa = 100 N e Ma = 300 Nm;",
    "Pa = 100 N e Ma = 100 Nm;",
    "Pa = 300 N e Ma = 100 Nm;"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A carbon non-alloyed steel at -80 ºC has a __________ than at +20 ºC:",
    answers: ["lower elongation;",
    "lower tensile strength;",
    "higher elongation;",
    "lower hardness."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A carbon non-alloyed steel at -80 ºC has a __________ than at +20 ºC:",
    answers: ["lower toughness;",
    "lower tensile strength;",
    "higher elongation;",
    "lower hardness."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding forces and stresses, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The torsional moment generates compressive stresses;",
    "A compressive force generates shear stresses;",
    "The tensile force generates normal stresses;",
    "The bending moment generates normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding forces and stresses, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The torsional moment generates compressive stresses;",
    "A compressive force generates shear stresses;",
    "The shear force generates shear stresses (neglecting the associated bending moment);",
    "The bending moment generates normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding forces and stresses, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The torsional moment generates compressive stresses;",
    "A compressive force generates shear stresses;",
    "The torsional moment generates shear stresses;",
    "The bending moment generates normal stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the forces, it can be said:",
    answers: ["If a rigid body is made up of several parts, the forces that hold these parts together are called external forces;",
    "A force applied to a rigid body always generates a moment;",
    "The force of action of one rigid body on another depends on the contact area;",
    "Distributed forces are those that act over an area of the body."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the forces, it can be said:",
    answers: ["The force of action of one rigid body on another depends on the contact area;",
    "A force applied to a rigid body always generates a moment;",
    "If a rigid body is made up of several parts, the forces that hold these parts together are called external forces;",
    "External forces are those that act on a body from outside."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the forces, it can be said:",
    answers: ["If a rigid body is made up of several parts, the forces that hold these parts together are called external forces;",
    "A force applied to a rigid body always generates a moment;",
    "The force of action of one rigid body on another depends on the contact area;",
    "Dynamic forces are time-depended."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the forces, it can be said:",
    answers: ["If a rigid body is made up of several parts, the forces that hold these parts together are called external forces;",
    "A force applied to a rigid body always generates a moment;",
    "The force of action of one rigid body on another depends on the contact area;",
    "A force can be exerted by contact or at a distance."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About notches, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["During welding, only internal notches occur, e.g., slag inclusions;",
    "Stress concentration caused by a notch does not lead to a reduction in fatigue strength, but it does reduce the yield point;",
    "Notches are typical imperfections of autogenous welding (mainly because of an incompletely filled groove);",
    "Notches cause stress concentration."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The higher the thermal expansion of a material, ...",
    answers: ["the greater mechanical strength it has.",
    "the greater ductility it has.",
    "the more prone to distortion it will be.",
    "the lower thermal conductivity it has."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In general, cracks are:",
    answers: ["intermetallic voids;",
    "planar defects caused by a metal rupture;",
    "metal shrinkage;",
    "a result of metal compression."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is not a measuring tool?",
    answers: ["Caliper.",
    "Level.",
    "Voltmeter.",
    "Micrometre."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The difference between a discontinuity and a defect is as follows:",
    answers: ["The defect is a large imperfection and the discontinuity is a small imperfection;",
    "Discontinuity is always a defect;",
    "A discontinuity is always unacceptable, while a defect may not affect the service of the part or component, depending on the application;",
    "Defects are discontinuities which are always outside the acceptable production error margins (acceptable limits). "],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The difference between a discontinuity and a defect is as follows:",
    answers: ["The defect is a large imperfection and the discontinuity is a small imperfection;",
    "Discontinuity is always a defect;",
    "A discontinuity is always unacceptable, while a defect may not affect the service of the part or component, depending on the application;",
    "A defect is a discontinuity that may compromise the service of the part, while a discontinuity is a failure that may or may not compromise the service of the part, depending on the application."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The difference between a discontinuity and a defect is as follows:",
    answers: ["The defect is a large imperfection and the discontinuity is a small imperfection;",
    "Discontinuity is always a defect;",
    "A discontinuity is always unacceptable, while a defect may not affect the service of the part or component, depending on the application;",
    "Discontinuity is an interruption of the typical structure of a physical body, with regard to the homogeneity of physical, mechanical or metallurgical characteristics;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The difference between a discontinuity and a defect is as follows:",
    answers: ["The defect is a large imperfection and the discontinuity is a small imperfection;",
    "Discontinuity is always a defect;",
    "A discontinuity is always unacceptable, while a defect may not affect the service of the part or component, depending on the application;",
    "A defect is a discontinuity that makes the part unfit for use, as it does not meet the minimum acceptance requirements of the applicable standard by its nature, type, dimensions, location or accumulated effect."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these is a non-destructive test:",
    answers: ["Ultrasonic.",
    "Charpy.",
    "Vickers hardness.",
    "Tensile test."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these is a non-destructive test:",
    answers: ["X-ray.",
    "Charpy.",
    "Vickers hardness.",
    "Tensile test."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these is a non-destructive test:",
    answers: ["Magnetic Particles inspection.",
    "Charpy.",
    "Vickers hardness.",
    "Tensile test."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these is a non-destructive test:",
    answers: ["Liquid Penetrant Inspection.",
    "Charpy.",
    "Vickers hardness.",
    "Tensile test."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Why are welding gas cylinders considered so dangerous?",
    answers: ["The gases in them are under pressure and the cylinders can explode.",
    "They will fall on your feet if not secured by chain.",
    "They are prone to fall down.",
    "They are very heavy and round shaped so they are awkward to handle."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is ventilation of the welding area important?",
    answers: ["It creates more comfortable conditions for welder.",
    "Ventilation pulls fumes away from the welding area, so that the visibility of the weld pool becomes much better.",
    "Some metal fumes can cause serious illness.",
    "The smoke from welding precipitates upon welding lenses."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In filler metal arc welding (by coated electrodes or MIG/MAG), the deposition rate is:",
    answers: ["higher at higher arc voltages;",
    "higher at higher welding currents;",
    "higher at longer arc lengths;",
    "independent of the electrical welding parameters and depends only on the feed rate of the filler metal (covered electrode or wire, respectively)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In consumable electrode arc welding, a variable that directly affects the deposition rate (defined as the weight of metal deposited per unit time) is:",
    answers: ["the inductance of the welding circuit (the greater the inductance, the greater the deposition rate);",
    "the arc voltage (the higher the voltage, the higher the deposition rate);",
    "the arc length (the greater the length, the greater the deposition rate);",
    "the welding current (the higher current, the greater deposition rate)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In consumable electrode arc welding, a variable that directly affects the deposition rate (defined as the weight of metal deposited per unit time) is:",
    answers: ["the inductance of the welding circuit (the greater the inductance, the greater the deposition rate);",
    "the arc voltage (the higher the voltage, the higher the deposition rate);",
    "the arc length (the greater the length, the greater the deposition rate);",
    "the electrode diameter (the smaller diameter, the higher deposition rate with the same welding current)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In consumable electrode arc welding, a variable that directly affects the deposition rate (defined as the weight of metal deposited per unit time) is:",
    answers: ["the inductance of the welding circuit (the greater the inductance, the greater the deposition rate);",
    "the arc voltage (the higher the voltage, the higher the deposition rate);",
    "the arc length (the greater the length, the greater the deposition rate);",
    "the electrode extension in MIG/MAG welding (the greater extension, the higher deposition rate with the same welding current)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the main constituent of the fume produced when MIG welding mild steel?",
    answers: ["Carbon monoxide.",
    "Carbon dioxide.",
    "Iron oxide.",
    "Filler metal oxide."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"}
];